Judgment is coming.
Nuremberg is a history, drama, thriller film directed by James Vanderbilt.
In postwar Germany, an American psychiatrist must determine whether Nazi prisoners are fit to go on trial for war crimes,
and finds himself in a complex battle of intellect and ethics with Hermann Göring, Hitler's right-hand man.
Hermann Göring, played by Russell Crowe.
Douglas Kelley, played by Rami Malek.
Justice Robert H. Jackson, played by Michael Shannon.
Sergeant Howie Triest, played by Leo Woodall.
Colonel Burton Andrus, played by John Slattery.
Sir David Maxwell-Fyfe, played by Richard E. Grant.
Nuremberg is a 2025 American psychological thriller historical drama film
written, co-produced, and directed by James Vanderbilt.
Based on the 2013 book The Nazi and the Psychiatrist
by Jack El-Hai, the film follows U.S.
Army psychiatrist Douglas Kelley (Rami Malek) seeking to carry out an assignment to investigate the personalities and monitor the mental
status of Hermann Göring (Russell Crowe) and other high-ranking Nazis in preparation for and during the Nuremberg trials.
Leo Woodall, John Slattery, Mark O'Brien, Colin Hanks,
Wrenn Schmidt, Lydia Peckham, Richard E.
Grant, and Michael Shannon have supporting roles in the film.
The film had its world premiere in the Gala Presentations section of the
Toronto International Film Festival on September 7, 2025.
It was released theatrically in the United States by Sony
Pictures Classics on November 7, 2025.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics,
with particular praise for Crowe's performance.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, nuremberg trials,
based on true story, nuremberg, germany, post world war ii.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking and intense.